恭喜，恭喜
Congratulations
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you
各位，想不到我葛大富这么大把年纪还生小孩
Hey, I can still make babies at this age
连我自己都不相信啊
I can't even believe it myself
各位，不用客气，多喝几杯酒
Everyone, drink some more
恭喜，恭喜，恭喜啦
Congratulations
小王八，王八嫂，我随便发发帖子
Hey Wang, I gave you the invitation
你们还真的跟来啦
Didn't think you would really come
我们只是路过，进来瞧一瞧而已
We're just passing through
我们听说你那么老了还生小孩，真不敢相信啊
Can't believe you can still make babies
你真会开玩笑，对了，上个月你小孩满月
Stop joking, oh, last month
我正好陪老婆待产，没办法看你去
My wife was in labor, so I couldn't see you
你小孩长什么样子，这么瘦小，一副贫贱相啊
Look at you kid, he has the poor look
没办法，家里穷嘛
Can't help it, we're poor
来，我看你那个宝贝长得什么样子
Come, let's see what your kid looks like
不用了，不用了
No need
当然要啦，今天的寿星，怎么可以不看呢？
Of course we do, it's his birthday today
长得肥肥白白的，挺可爱的嘛
White and chubby, he's kind of cute
谢谢
Thank you
小寿星，争气点，能活多久算多久
Birthday boy, live as long as you can
开玩笑的，那么认真干什么呢？
I'm just kidding, why be so serious
小孩取名字没有？
Did you give him a name yet?
取好了，叫葛长寿
His name is Long-life
葛长寿，这么俗气啊？
Long-life? That's tacky
我已经替他想好名字了，改名改名！
I have another name for him
改什么？
What?
改名叫葛屁
Call him Fart
葛屁
Fart
你们说，葛屁是不是比葛长寿好听啊？
Tell me, isn't it a lot better?
八哥，你开玩笑也该有个限度
Ba, there should be a limit to your jokes
葛大嫂，可别生气啊
Mrs. Ko, don't get angry
王八蛋，你跟你儿子一起滚蛋
Wang, take you and your son our of here
滚蛋，贺礼我送了，满月酒不让我喝
I gave you a gift already
有没有搞错啊？
How can you tell me to leave?
要我走可以啊，贺礼还给我
Fine, if you want me to go give my gift back
没这么回事
No way
你们又在吵什么？
What are you arguing about
富哥，八哥，你们俩只要在一块，声音就这么大
Fu, Ba, you two are always so loud together
都当了爹了，老毛病还不改
You're a father already, can't even change
小咪
Mee
站住
Stop
我要招呼客人嘛
I have to greet the guest
我来招呼就好了
I'll greet her for you
干什么？你们两个还没有死心啊？
You two haven't given up?
人家女儿都有了，我还能不死心吗？
She has a daughter already, how can I not?
还好当初我没娶她
Luckily I didn't marry her
你看她老公，应该是命不久矣啊
Doesn't look like her husband will live long
你知道就好了
As long as you know
富哥，八哥，你们好
Fu, Ba, how are you?
老胡，你脸色愈来愈差，要多保重啊
Hu, you look awful, you should take care
谁叫我当初不听八哥的劝
Too bad I didn't to Ba before
明知道自己的命没有她硬，去硬要娶她
I shouldn't have married her
失礼，失礼了
Sorry
老爷，一眉道长到了
Sir, the priest is here
快请，快请
Invite him in
是
Yes sir
是那一个一眉道长啊？
What priest?
城里有名抓鬼捉妖的一眉道长
The one that's famous for catching ghosts
请他来干什么？
Why invite him here?
帮我小孩算命纳福
To tell the fortune of my kid
来了
He's here
师父，请
This way Master
一眉道长
Priest
我叫你准备的东西，准备好了没有？
Did you prepare the things?
东西都准备好了，请
Yes, please
道长，这是我小孩的生辰八字
Priest, my kid's birth date and time
一眉道长，到底我孩子的命运怎么样，好不好？
How's the fortune of my kid, is it good?
你要先听我说，还是先我徒弟说？
You want to hear me first or my student?
有分别吗？
Is there a difference?
你先说
You go first
是
OK
恭喜老爷，贺喜夫人，您的小孩福禄双全
Congratulations, youi son has a good fortune
将来不是个文秀才嘛
He'll either be a scholar
就是个武状元，而且长命百岁，寿与天齐
Or a general, and he'll live long and healthy
恭喜发财，红包拿来
Congratulations, please give a reward
红包，红包
Here you are
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you
怎么样？
What?
他的话你都听完了，现在轮到我说
Now it's my turn
第一，我要澄清一件事情
First, I'll make one thing clear
刚才那段话只属于个人意见
That was only his personal opinion
与本道长无关
It has nothing to do with me
究竟我小孩的命怎么样啊？
So how is my son's fortune?
他取了名字没有？
Have you given him a name yet?
取了，叫葛长寿
Yes, Long-life
名字还不错
Pretty good name
不过呢，与他的本命刚刚好相反
But it's directly opposite from his fate
什么意思？
What do you mean?
他生于丁卯三月初三，所谓三月三，度难关
He was born on March the third
难关，难关，依我看，他是难过二十三
It's my opinion that he won't live past 23
这个小孩，生于阴年阴月阴日
This child was born on a negative date
所谓阴盛自必阳衰
Therefore his positive energy is low
二十三正好是他的一个难关
His 23rd year is a hard one for him to cross
每逢初一十五月圆之时，也是阳气最弱的时候
He'll be weak when the moon is full
因此月圆之夜要特别注意
So you should be careful during the full moon
你放屁
That's garbage
你那么大声干什么，把小孩子都吓哭了
Be quiet, you'll scare the kid
小孩并是他吓哭的，各位，你们看看外面的月亮
Everyone, look at the moon outside
今天的月亮真的好圆喔
The moon is full today
大师，那怎么办呢？
What should I do?
起坛
Set up the table
一饼，天下动
The first, moves the earth
二饼，凶神恶煞走千里
The second, gets rid of the ghosts
三饼，走世界
The third, walks the earth
四饼，甲威灵
The fourth, strengthens the soul
五饼，圣祖力
The fifth, calls up the saints
各路神兵来报到，十万火急如律令
All you gods report at once
儿子还真的不哭了
The kid really stopped crying
做父母的最好能够替他多积阴德
As his parents, you should do good deeds
希望他能够撑过二十三
I hope he can make it past 23
之后就可以一帆风顺了
After that he'll be fine
对不起，也许我说的话不太好听
Excuse me, maybe I didn't say good things
但是红包还是免不了
But you must give me a reward
红包啊，给他
Give him the reward
他们两个要不要给我算一算命？
Do you need their fortunes told?
不用了，不用了
No, no
葛老爷，我还忘了补充你一句话
Mr. Ko, I need to tell you something else
你的长寿仔，是属于少年老成的
Your son will mature early
终于听到你说一句好话了
Finally, something good
原来你说我长寿仔是少年稳重那种
So, you're saying my son will be dignified
不是，我说的少年老成是指你儿子老得很快
No, I'm saying your son will age quickly
请
Please
精英社
Elite Club
杀无赦
Kill no pardon
武圣，武圣
Saint Club
逢打必胜
Undefeatable
干什么你？
What are you doing?
大家不要冲动
Calm down
不要动
Don't move
先进去再说嘛
Let's go in first
请
Speak
秀秀
Hsio
白大嫂，你今天特别漂亮
Mrs. Pai, you're extra pretty today
一包花生
A bag of peanuts
好
OK
你的耳环好美哦
Your earrings are beautiful
是真的吗？
Is it real?
是啊
Yes it is
一瓶汽水
A bottle of soda
好
OK
你的发簪好特别，一定很贵
Your hair clip must be expensive
是啊，是真的很贵，你还挺识货的
Yes it is, your pretty sharp
这些东西全帮我包起来
Wrap these up for me
好
OK
乡长，请用茶
Have some tea chief
谢谢你，小咪，清洁队的工作还习惯吗？
Thank you, Mee, how's the cleaning job?
很习惯，谢谢
It's fine, thank you
不要再忙了，坐着看比赛吧
Why don't you sit and watch the competition?
好的，谢谢
Alright, thank you
娘
Mom
秀秀，今天卖这么多啦
Hsio you sold so many today
对呀，白大嫂就买了一大堆呢
Yeah, Mrs. Pai bought a bunch
她买这么多干什么？
Why did she buy so many?
因为我一直夸她这个好看，那个漂亮啊
I kept on telling her how pretty she was
你呀，就是这张嘴
You and your mouth
大家安静，请安静
Quiet everybody
各位乡亲父老，欢迎各位今天来参加
Welcome everyone
本乡一年一度的擂台赛最后决赛
The final for our annual competition
在我左手边的是王八弟师父所教出来的武圣堂
On my left is Mr. Wang's Saint Club
在我右手边的是葛大富先生所赞助的精英社
On my right is Mr. Ko's Elite Club
今天的裁判是本乡的保安队队长郝清明先生
The referee is our police Captain Mr. Hao
各位，各位，现在比赛马上开始
Everyone, the competition is about to begin
谢谢各位，谢谢，谢谢
Thank you, thank you
比赛开始
Start the competition
加油.
Come on...
打.
Hit him...
星哥，你要什么？
Sing, what do you want?
我要秀秀
I want Hsio
你打赢了就给你
Only if you win
要什么？
What do you want?
我要秀秀
I want Hsio
等你过了二十三岁以后再说吧
Wait until you're over 23
把她卖到妓院去吧
Sell her to the brothel
卖你的头
I'll sell you head
精英社获胜
Elite Club win
阿森，你上
Sen, you're up
武圣堂获胜
Saint Club win
好，现在是一比一平手，剩下最后一个回合
OK, it's a one to one tie, only one more round
谁赢了，谁就是今年的冠军
Who ever wins is this year's champion
阿星，输赢就看你的了
Sing, it's in your hands
星哥，你要小心点
Sing, be careful
星哥加油.
Come on Sing
他已经收了我们的钱了，所以你是稳赢的
He already took our money, you'll win for sure
你的任务是不要让他输的太轻松，愈难看愈好
Your job is to make him look bad
好壮的男人，小咪，你认不认识，帮我介绍一下
He's strong, do you know him, introduce to me
我认识他爹，中看不中用
I know his father, he's not that strong
打.
Hit him...
住手
Stop
谁都不准拿
No one is allowed to take this
可以让我下去了吧？
Can I go down now?
不要卖东西了，来，钱给你，看阿星怎么输吧
Stop selling, let's go watch Sing lose
你怎么输得那么惨？
Why did you lose that bad?
星哥，你不能输啊
Sing, you can't lose
他能不输吗？
How can he not lose
你们耍我
You tricked me
星哥，加油
Come on Sing
我要让他输得更难看
I want him to lose worse
荡回来.
Get it back...
武圣堂获胜
Saint Club wins
武圣，武圣
Saint Club, Saint Club
逢打必胜
Undefeatable
今天的冠军是武圣堂，现在我们请乡长颁奖
Today's winner is the Saint Club
谢谢
Thank you
等一等
Wait
我们赢了，你抢什么？
We won, what do you want?
我不是跟你们抢这个奖杯
I'm not here to fight for the trophy
我是来跟你要回你儿子答应打假拳的红包
I'm here to collect from your son
阿星，是不是真的？
Sing is this true?
对不起.
I'm sorry...
爹，爹.
Dad...
你还不快点去追
Go after him
你没事吧？
Are you alright?
我没事
I'm fine
小姐，对不起，撞到你了
Miss, excuse me
没想到被你弹到这么运
You are strong
你撞的不是我
You didn't bump into me
不是你？
No?
不是
No
你撞到的是我，不是她
You bumped into me, not her
是你啊，不会吧，你身上有这么大弹力？
You, can't be, you're that strong?
要不要再试试啊？
Want to try again?
不用了，我有事，我要先走了
No need, I'm leaving
爹，爹.
Dad
别看了，可以走了
You can leave now
没想到我们武圣堂的威名
The name of the Saint Club
今天毁在你这个狗儿子手上
Has been destroyed by you bastard
爹，我是想就算我们赢了
Dad, even if we won
拿个烂奖杯了什么用，又不值钱，所以我就.
We only get a cheap trophy, so I...
所以你卑鄙无耻，做下流的事
So you disgraced us
收老葛的钱，打假拳是不是？
Buy accepting Mr. Ko's money, right?
我要好好教训你
I'm going to teach you a good lesson
住手，小孩子嘛，做错了点事情有那么严重
Stop, he's only a kid, it's no big deal
你非把他给打死不成吗？
Are you going to kill him?
不好好打他一顿，我还有脸见人吗？
Do I have any dignity left?
你把他打死了
If you kill him
你有脸去见你那死去多年的老婆吗？
How are you going to face your dead wife?
好了好了，你先出去吧
Fine, leave
我来帮你教训星仔就成了
I'll punish him for you
免得你是打在儿身，痛在父心啊
So you don't get hurt yourself
好，阿星就交给你了，你们出去打扫庭院
Fine, I'll leave him to you, go clean up
是
Alright
师父，请喝茶
Please have some tea
胡妈妈，我知道错了，你不要再打了
Mrs. Hu, I know my mistake
没想到你会这么没出息
I'm disappointed in you
这些钱给你，你也有脸收，真是没出息透了你
You have the guts to accept this money
师父，胡妈妈好像打得很厉害
It sounds like Mrs. Hu is beating him
少听他们在那演戏了
They doing it for show
好了，出去让你爹看看打得够不够
OK, go let your father take a look
不够再进来打啊
Come back in if it's not enough
爹
Dad
阿星
Sing
你看看够不够，不够我再打
Did I beat him enough?
干嘛，你要把他打死啊？
What, do you want to kill him?
你不是要把他给打死吗，怎么，心疼啦？
Why, you don't have to heart?
你也用不着这么认真嘛
You didn't have to take me that seriously
阿星，你没事吧？/AreyouOK？
Are you OK?
没事
Fine
八叔，我带星哥回家上点药
Uncle Ba, I'll go put some medicine on him
好，好，快去，快去
Go, hurry
走好啊
Take care
我以为你开玩笑的，怎么玩真的？
I thought you were joking, why so serious?
谁跟你开玩笑啊
Who's joking
还好当年没有娶她
Luckily I didn't marry her
那个什么打通省、港、澳的窝囊废
What a phony
是从什么地方找来的？
Where did they find him?
老爹，你不要骂我，要骂就骂他们两个好了
Don't blame me, blame them
是他们介绍给我
They introduced us
说什么他是今年的省、港、澳拳王啊
Said they were champs
我看他是挨扁拳王，走.
What phonies, let's go...
走啦
Let's go
没用的东西
Useless
看吧，都是你
It's all your fault
这怎么能怪我？
Why me?
儿子，你把他们两个留在身边做什么？
Son, why do you keep them next to you?
没他们陪我很无聊啊
I'm lonely without them
他们只会陪你叫鸡，陪你赌钱，陪你搞事
They're bad influences on you
你要人陪，为什么不肯好好找个老婆陪你呢？
If you want company why not get married?
你知道我很喜欢秀秀，可是她不喜欢我
I like Hsio, but she doesn't like me
她喜欢阿星啊
She likes Sing
王八蛋的儿子怎么能跟你大少爷比呢？
How can he compare with you?
你真的很喜欢秀秀是不是？
You really like Hsio?
是啊？
Yes
那跟我走
Come with me
去那里？
Where to?
提亲啊
To propose
提亲？
Propose
你画得可真像，连我爹都被你给骗了
Your drawing is so real
那要谢谢我妈
Thanks to my mom
对呀，我一定看到你跟你妈来
Yeah, I saw your mom
我就知道我今天可以逃过一劫了
I knew I'd be lucky today
我爹还是那么喜欢你妈，真难得
My dad still likes your mom
我就是一直耽心这个问题
I've been worried about that
要是我妈最后肯答应嫁给八叔
If my mom married your dad
那我们就会变成兄妹
Then we'll be siblings
想要一起也没有希望了嘛
There goes our future
可是我爹一直不敢跟你妈开口啊
My dad is afraid to ask your mom
我现在只希望我妈妈最后肯答应嫁给葛老爷
I wish my mom will promise to marry Mr. Ko
那我们就不怕变成兄妹
Then we won't be siblings
也不怕长寿仔再来缠我了
Long-life won't bug me anymore
小李
Lee
秀秀，米送来了
Hsio, here's your rice
放那边就好了
Put it over there
不好，不好，如果你妈妈嫁给了葛老爷
No, if your mom marries Mr. Ko
那长寿仔就变成你哥哥
Then Long-life will be your brother
我以后想要见你，不就更麻烦了吗？
It will be difficult for me to see you
那也比我们是兄妹好啊
It's better than being related
秀秀，你们为什么不去跟他们凑凑热闹啊？
Hsio, why don't you go with them?
凑什么热闹啊？
What for?
葛老爷在大厅要跟你妈妈提亲啊
Mr. Ko is proposing to your mom
你很快就要改姓葛了
You will be Miss Ko soon
葛老爷跟我妈提亲？
Propose to my mom?
那太好了，我们快去撮合他们，走啊
Great, let's go pursuade her
老葛，你们寿仔跟我们秀秀提亲
Mr. Ko, Long-lifes' proposal to Hsio
这件事情，我真的不能答应你
I cannot accept
胡妈妈，你先问问秀秀嘛
Mrs. Hu, why not ask Hsio
或许她看到这么多么礼物，就答应了呢
Maybe she'll agree
是啊
Yeah
妈，葛老爷
Mom, Mr. Ko
葛老爷，胡妈妈
Mr. Ko, Mrs. Hu
秀秀，来
Hsio, come
哇，这么多礼物啊
Wow, all these gifts
好了，好了，先别看这些东西了
Forget these things for now
我有件事情要跟你商量呢
I have to discuss something with you
不用商量了，我已经知道怎么回事了
I already know
其实人生大事迟早都是要面对的嘛
Everyone has to get married sooner or later
原来你.
So you...
胡妈妈，不止秀秀知道，连我都知道了
Mrs. Hu, even I know
连你都知道了，那你怎么都不紧张呢？
Even you, then why aren't you nervous
我有什么好紧张的，该紧张的应该是你才对啊
You should be nervous
对不对？
Right?
对啊
Right
我？
Me?
秀秀，既然我们的目的你知道了
Hsio, since you know
那你自己的意思怎么样？
What is your opinion?
要是妈肯答应，我还能说什么呢？葛老爷
If my mom says yes, then what can I say?
小咪，你听到了吧，秀秀都说没意见
Mee, you heard, Hsio has no objections
那我们就这么说罗
Then it's settled
秀秀，你真的肯答应吗？
Hsio, are you sure?
我当然答应
Of course
星仔，那你呢？
Sing, and you?
我举双手赞成
I agree
星仔，我跟你从小玩到大
Sing, we been friends since kids
今天才知道你这么大方，谢谢，谢谢
You are so kind, thank you
不客气啦
You're welcome
既然秀秀跟星仔都答应了，我还能怎么样呢？
Since Hsio and Sing both agree, so do I
好吧，这门亲事就这么订了
OK, then it's settled
妈，恭喜你
Mom, congratulations
你们两个恭喜我们两个老人家干什么？
Why congratulate us?
秀秀，你应该恭喜你自己才对啊
Hsio, you should congratulate yourself
星仔，你应该恭喜我们长寿啊
Sing you should congratulate Long-life
我为什么要恭喜我自己啊？
Congratulate myself?
因为你妈妈刚刚已经答应了你跟我的亲事
Your mom just agreed to our marriage
什么？
What?
胡妈妈，不是葛老爷向你提亲吗？
Mrs. Hu, Mr. Ko didn't propose to you?
你想那儿去了
Of course not!
他是替他们长寿仔来跟我们家秀秀提亲的
They're here to propose to Hsio
对，是我啊，你们还没搞清楚啊？
Didn't you get it straight?
妈，我们搞错了，我不能嫁给他，我不能嫁给他
Mom, we made a mistake, I'm not marrying him
你刚才已经看见我答应老葛了
You saw me promise Mr. Ko
你又不是不知道我的脾气
You should know me
答应的事情绝不反悔
I never go back on my word
不行，这次一定要反悔
This time you must
不行，老葛，你这些聘礼我都收了
No, Mr. Ko I'm accepting the gifts
我们再来谈谈酒席跟聘金的问题
Let's talk about the other details
那当然，那当然啦
Of course
秀秀，开始你可能会不太习惯
Hsio, might be awkward at first
慢慢的你就会知道我的好处了
But you'll know my good side
秀秀，没关系嘛，秀秀
Hsio, no problem
秀秀.
Hsio...
你不要哭了嘛，好不好？
Stop crying
他们已经在谈细节的问题了，我能不哭吗？
How can I not?
你一哭，我就六神无主了啦
I get nervous when you cry
你先静一静，让我想想办法，好不好？
Calm down, let me think, OK?
那你快想啊
Hurry
去找我爹
Let go find my dad
你爹，找他有用吗？
Will he help?
我有办法让他帮忙的，来
I'll make him help, come
什么，老葛都那么一大把年纪了
What, Ko at his age
还敢跟小咪提亲说要娶她？
Wants to marry Mee?
所以我们一知道了，就赶快回来告诉你呀
So we came over as soon as we heard
八叔，我知道你还是很爱我娘的
Uncle Ba, I know you love my Mon
你要赶快想办法阻止他们啊
You must stop them
要不然你就没有机会了
Otherwise you'll lose your chance
岂有此理，无所谓，让我狠狠教训他
Outrageous, I'm going to teach him a lesson
你们商量一下吧
Discuss among yourselves
老葛，你觉得他们的亲事
Mr. Ko, do you think the wedding
是应该采用中式的好呢，还是西式的好呢？
Should be Chinese or Western style?
你倒是想好了没有？
Have you decided?
神兵火急如律令
God's soldier hurry
其实什么式我都没意见，只要大家舒服就行了
As long as everyone is comfortable it's fine
是啊，是啊
That's right
你知道，我年纪大了
You know, I'm old
高难度的动作，我可能不行哦
I can't do tough movements
爹地，你说什么？
Dad, what are you talking about?
大人讲话，小孩不要插嘴
Stay out of it
小咪，你最喜欢那一招啊，说给我听
Mee, tell me which style you like
只要难度别太高，我一定配合
I'll do it for you if it's not tough
你疯了你？
Are you crazy?
我是疯了
Yes I am
小咪，这么多年来我真的想你想得快疯了
I'm crazy about you Mee
其实我每次看到你，我就想剥下你的衣服
I want to rip your clothes off
爬到你的身上，然后.
Climb on you, and then...
你们俩都给我滚
Both of you get lost
未来岳母，你先别发脾气，我爹一定是鬼上身了
Future mother-in-law please don't be angry
我先打醒他
I'll hit him
老爸他也敢打
You dare hit your father?
你们要是再不滚，我就通通打
If you don't get lost, I'll hit you
我打了，我一起打
I'll beat up all of you
我打死你
I'll kill you
等等我.
Wait for me...
好，好，算你跑得快
Lucky for you you run fast
以后再也不准进我们家门了
Don't ever come to my house again
小咪
Mee
岳母大人
Mother-in-law
好了，老爸
OK Dad
你这样，我的终身幸福全毁在你手上了
You ruined my future
我做了什么了？
What did I do?
你刚才跟人家胡妈妈说
You told Mrs. Hu
你要剥光她的衣服，然后爬到她身上.
You want to rip her clothes off...
我怎么把埋藏在心底的话都说出来啊
Why did I say what I was thinking?
老葛，这个世界上又不是只有小咪一个女人
Mr. Ko, find another woman
我也是女人啊，我还可以让你剥
I can let you rip off my clothes
让你爬
Let you climb
我还可以让你.
I can let you...
干什么都可以
Do what ever
真的啊？
Really?
当然是真的啦，来嘛.
Of course, come...
老爸，你干什么，老命都不要了？
Dad, what are you doing?
老葛，你什么意思嘛，吊人家味口
Mr. Ko, what's the idea of teasing me
对不起，我年纪大了，不想死在牡丹花下
Sorry, I'm old and don't want to die in bed
走啦，走啦
Let's go
天下又不是只有你一个男人，有什么了不起嘛
You're not the only man in this world
老爸，你真的不想活了？
Dad, you really don't want to live?
秀秀
Hsio
老葛，小咪是不是答应嫁你了？
Mr. Ko, did Mee promise to marry you?
一定是你这个王八蛋搞的鬼
You bastard
八叔，我知道你会妖法，但是也不是那么卑鄙
Ba, I didn't think you'd stoop so low
我没有啊
I didn't
你还说没有
Don't deny it
不要跟他罗嗦，这个仇我早晚会报的
Don't argue with him, we'll get him later
秀秀，那些礼物还是给给你
Hsio, those gifts are for you
走啦，不要罗嗦了
Shut up, let's go
少爷，你不要这样闷闷不乐的嘛
Don't be so unhappy
就是说嘛，我们再去万花楼怎么样？
How about we go to the brothel?
你就知道嫖，能不能想点别的？
Can't you think of something else?
少爷，那我们干脆回家练大字好了
Let's go practice our penmanship
练你妈的大头字，你写啊？
Penmanship?
那你想怎么样嘛？
Then what?
我想怎么样有什么用呢？
Want difference does it make?
我说想让秀秀在我面前脱光
I want Hsio to undress in front of me
可能吗？没有可能嘛
It's impossible
有可能的，少爷
It's possible
快点上去
Hurry up
有没有搞错，看女人嘛，弄的我一身汗
You got me all sweaty
少爷，要不要.
Do you want to...
快点，我等不及了，快.
Hurry I can't wait...
快.
Hurry
哇，正点
What a body
原来是胡妈妈
It's Mrs. Hu
总比没有好啊
Better than nothing
是啊，没想到她妈的身材也不错
She's not bad either
还说，走了啦
Let's go
妈，洗好了没有，轮到我洗了
Mom, are you done, it's my turn
就好了
Soon
不准看，不准看
Don't look
为什么嘛？
Why?
搞不好秀秀以后就是我老婆
Hsio might be my future wife
少爷，你没听过好东西要跟好朋友分享的吗？
Haven't you heard of sharing?
这个也能跟好朋友分享，走啦，走啦
Not this, let's go
少爷，你小心点
Be careful
少爷.
Master...
开门啊
Open up
怎么了？
What?
快走啊
Hurry up
长寿仔你.
Long-life, you...
秀秀
Hsio
秀秀，你怎么了？
Hsio, what's wrong?
孩子，秀秀.
My child, Hsio...
娘，你没看到我吗？
Mom, can't you see me?
娘，我在这儿呢
I'm over here
娘.
Mom...
秀秀，你怎么就这么离娘而去啊？
Hsio, why did you leave me like this?
难道我真的.
Am I...
娘.
Mom...
小咪，好了好了，不要难过了
Don't be sad
到底葛大富跟长寿仔
Ko and Long-life
这两个禽兽父子抓到了没有啊？
Have they caught those animals yet?
什么禽兽父子
What animals?
葛老爷是这里有头有脸的大富商
Mr. Ko is a prominent businessman
再说，无凭无据的，我凭什么去抓人啊？
Plus, without evidence how can I arrest them?
我请他们都来不及
I can't even invite them
葛老爷
Mr. Ko
葛老爷您好
Hello Mr. Ko
你好
Hello
不要乱来，这是公堂，你以为是你家啊
Don't fool around, this is a court
葛老爷，您好，请上坐
Mr. Ko, please have a seat
请坐，坐，坐.
Please sit
好，来，坐下来
OK, fine
不要哭了，郝队长他是个清官
Quit crying, Captain is a good man
他一定会查一个水落石出的
He'll get to the bottom of this
好了，现在有什么事情可以老老实实的告诉我了
Ok, tell me the truth
葛长寿，你先讲
You first Mr. Ko
队长，秀秀发生事情那一天我正好路过那里
I was just passing by that day
没想到胡妈妈她就误会我.
Mrs. Hu mistaken me...
你少来了
Come on
长寿仔，一定是那天你跟两个狐群狗党
Long-life, you and your friends
偷看秀秀洗澡，然后把屋顶弄垮，压死了秀秀
Crushed the ceiling and killed Hsio
你还不承认？
Do you still deny it?
阿星，不要冲动，让我来
Sing, calm down, let me
保安队长，请你.
Captain, please...
请我什么？
What?
请你分清楚，不要听我儿子片面之词
Don't listen to my son
冤枉了长寿仔
Falsely accuse Long-life
对啊，对啊
Yeah
你疯了你？
Are you crazy?
爹，你说什么？
Dad, what are you saying?
我就是没疯才会这么说的
I say this because I'm not crazy
郝队长，那以你多年来查案、办案、审案
According to your experience
翻案的经验，你对本案有什么看法啊？
What is your view?
我只有一个结论
I only have one conclusion
因为胡家的房子太日，年久失修
Because the Hu residence is too old
所以呢才会造成这个意外
This accident happened
所以呢，我判葛长寿无罪，就此结案，谢谢各位
So, I find Long-life not guilty, case closed
队长，你真是明白事理，明白是非
Captain, you are really sharp
真是明明白白
Very precise
爹，我看你明明神经有问题，他这样把.
Dad, I think you're crazy
不过说真的
But seriously
胡妈妈，你们家的房子也实在太破了
Mrs. Hu, your house is really old
我看，改天我去帮你们修修啊
I'll come and fix it for you
星仔，连你也疯了？
Sing, are you crazy too?
阿星，你跟你老爸把小咪搞定就行了
Sing take care of Mrs. Hu
好了，队长，没什么事我先走了
OK captain, I'm leaving
送葛老爷
Goodbye
送葛少爷，请
你不能走，你还我秀秀的命来
Give me back my Hsio
我们回去再说
Let's go home first
对呀，你们有空回去修一修自己的房子
Yeah, go fix your house
不要诬赖别人，这是不对的呀
Don't harass others, it's not right
胡妈妈
Mrs. Hu
刚才我爹真的是被保安队长挟持住
My Dad was being threatened by the captain
所以他才帮他们说话的
That's why he acted strange
秀秀死得好冤枉啊
Hsio died so innocently
以保安队长跟老葛的交情
Looking at captain and Ko's friendship
用屁股想都知道他会怎么做的
You can imagine what he would do
对啊，胡妈妈，我爹说得对
Yes, my dad's right
秀秀，娘没有用，娘不能替你讨回个公道来
Hsio, I can't revenge your death
有道是冤有头，债有主
I'm helpless
我看这个仇，只有你自己去报了
You can revenge your death
告诉你，我要看到长寿仔他真的死于非命
I want to see Long-life die miserably
我就知道，你是报了仇了
So I know you revenged your death
只要是长寿仔他一天不死
As long as he's alive
娘是绝对不会把你埋葬的
Mom won't bury you
你不把秀秀埋葬，会发臭的
She'll stink if you don't bury her
臭
Stink
臭，那是我们家的事，关你屁事啊？
That's our problem, not yours
怎么不关我事啊？
Not mine?
对对对，我们就像是自家人一样
Yeah, were like a family
胡妈妈的事就是我们的事嘛
Your business is our business
就因为是自家人，我才叫她把秀秀快埋葬掉
I suggest you bury her
我是关心啊
I'm concerned
你关心什么？
About what?
我们就住你们对面啊
We live across from you
这尸体发臭，会传到我们那边去啊
Our house will stink too
你怕的是这个
That's your concern
我还真以为，你把我们俩母女的事情
And I really thought
当做是你们的事呢
You cared
胡妈妈，你放心，秀秀的事就是我的事
Mrs. Hu, Hsio's business is my business
阿森，我们走
Sen, let's go
你们去那里啊？
Where are you going?
寿仔，他的名字叫联军，以后就是你的贴身保镖
Long-life, this is Lieng you body guard
联军？为什么那么奇怪啊？
Lieng? What a strange name?
听说在八国联军围京的时候
Long time ago
他妈妈被轮暴，怀孕，结果就生下了他
His mom was gang raped and had him
所以呢，他就叫做联军
So he's called Lieng
这么说他是个杂种了？
This means he's a bastard
你可以叫我混血，但是不可以叫我杂种
You can call me mixed, but not bastard
我忘了告诉你们
I forgot to tell you
搞不好他的中文好过你们
His Chinese might be better than yours
老爷，你怎么不早说呢？
Why didn't you say so
就不知道能不能打，你们试试看
Can he fight, try him
我不用试了，我已经尝过他的厉害了
No need, I tried already
你叫老么来试试看吧
You try it
我？不用试了，我肯定他行的
Me? No need, I'm certain he's good
不试怎么知道，上啊
How would you know if you didn't try?
长寿仔
Long-life
保安队长不制裁你，秀秀的仇我来报
I'm here to revenge Hsio's death
少爷，我想应该不用我试了吧？
Master, I don't need to try anymore?
联军，这两个人没有礼貌，帮我请他出去
Lieng, get rid of them
联军，你干嘛那么客气，把他们轰出去
儿子，厉害吧？
Pretty good, eh?
不是厉害，是非常厉害
Very good
你混蛋
You bastard
杂种打得好，上啊
The bastard can fight
吐口水
Spit
我不是来打架的，我是来找儿子跟徒弟的
I'm here to find my son not to fight
好在你来得快，再晚点来他们俩就被打死了
Fortunately you're here before they're killed
我们走
Let's go
幸好八叔把他们带走得早
Fortunately Ba took them
再晚一点他们就要用抬的了
Any later they would have been carried out
是啊是啊，少爷，还好你跑得快
Yeah, fortunately you ran fast
他们追得连腿都快要断掉了
They chased pretty hard
是吗，我上去撒泡尿他们就走了？
Yeah, I'll piss on them?
是啊，都走了
Yeah
好在他们都跑得快
Luckily they ran fast
姑娘，你为什么不穿衣服？
Miss, why aren't you wearing clothes?
你们是.
You are...
我是吊死鬼
We're ghosts
我是调皮鬼
I'm the mischief ghost
我是淹死鬼
I'm the drowning ghost
我是.
I'm...
不用说了，一看就知道你是个色鬼
You must be a horny ghost
那你是什么鬼？
What kind of ghost are you?
我也不知道
I don't know
她是什么鬼？
What kind is she?
你是羞羞鬼
She's a shy ghost
各位鬼大哥，我是新鬼，要去鬼门关报到
Hello everyone, I'm new
但是不知道该怎么走
I don't know where to go
我们也是要去报到的
We're going the same way
那我可以跟你们一起去了？
Can I follow you?
看你这副德性，你进得了鬼门关才怪呢
You'll never get past the gate
不要理她，我们走
Ignore her, lets go
鬼大哥，你们别走啊，鬼大哥
Please don't go
我从来没有见过这么厉害的洋鬼子
I've never seen such a tough foreigner
有他在长寿的身边，秀秀的仇没得报了
lt'll be hard to revenge for Hsio
平常叫你们好好练功，你们不练
I told you people to practice
两个打一个都打不赢，你们丢不丢人？
You people are embarrassing
什么丢人嘛，你不知道啊
Don't you know
他是八国联军生下来的杂种
He's the son of foreign troops
大清朝都对付不了八国联军
Even the Emperor couldn't defeat them
更何况我们只有两个人，怎么赢啊？
So how do you expect us two to do it?
怎么赢，下次我打给你们看
I'll show you next time
真的啊？
Really?
八叔，星哥，八叔
Uncle Ba, Sing
谁在叫我？
Who's calling me?
没有啊
I didn't hear anything
秀秀
Hsio
爹，你看到秀秀了，秀秀在那里？
Dad, you saw her, where is she?
就在你面前
Right in front of you
秀秀
Hsio
星哥
Sing
你看不到的
You can't see her
爹，你帮我开天眼，我要见秀秀啦
Dad help me see her
不行
No
为什么嘛？
Why not?
因为她没穿衣服
Because she's naked
你看到秀秀没穿衣服？
You're looking at her naked?
废话
Of course
师父，你不帮师兄开，那帮我开
Master, help me see her too
你想干什么，听到秀秀光屁股，你想看是吧
Do you want to see her naked?
是啊
Yeah
好，想开天眼，我不会，k你我会
I'll beat you up
好了好了，你们先回去
OK, you go back first
爹，那你呢？
Dad, what about you?
我要帮秀秀穿衣服
I'm going to get Hsio some clothes
我只能帮你到这里了
I can only help you this much
因为我不是你的亲人，不可以烧衣服给你
Because I'm not your relative
明天，我会叫你娘给你烧衣服的
Tomorrow I'll tell your mom to get you more
谢谢八叔
Thank you
你娘她不只是命硬，脾气更硬
Your mom is really stubborn
她说你不找长寿仔报仇，讨回公道
She said if you don't revenge you death
她就不把你安葬
She won't bury you
那我怎么报仇呢？
How do I revenge my death?
先别说了，先去鬼门关报到
First, you must report to the gate of death
鬼门关在那里啊？
Where's that?
一直往西走就是了
Keep going towards the west
八叔，你怎么那么清楚呢，你去过鬼门关？
How do you know, have you been there?
大吉大利，童言无’忌，你咒我？
Stop curse me
我不是咒你
I'm not
只是你怎么知道鬼门关是往西边走呢？
But how do you know?
人死了就叫归西嘛，傻瓜
When people die, they go west
我看啊你不只是个羞羞鬼
You're not only a shy ghost
你还是个笨鬼呢，快点走吧
You're also stupid, go
别说话，排好
Stop talking, stand still
档案编号
File number
二年四月十号
April 10th, 1914
好，走，下一个
OK, next
我叫胡秀秀
My name is Hsio Hu
穿整齐一点，再回来报到，快走
Put some clothes on and come back
少爷
Master
来，再喝，再喝.
Come, drink
不行不行，少爷，不能再喝了
No master, I can't
为什么不能再喝？
Why not?
今天晚上是十五月圆夜，万一有什么事情的话呢
There's a full moon out tonight
不会有什么事情的啦
Nothing will happen
老爷怪罪我们担不起啊
We can afford to take the blame
好.那买单
Fine... Check
店长
Waiter
买单了
The check
只要是长寿仔一天不死
As Long-life lives a day
娘是绝对不会把你埋葬的
Mom will not bury you
你干什么你？
What are you doing?
对不起，对不起
Sorry
你们快过来，有东西飞过来，飞过来了
Come over here, there's something flying
秀秀
Hsio
秀你妈个头
Hsio you head
真的，我看见了，我真的看见了嘛
Really, I saw her
别跑
Don't run
哇，难道秀秀的身材这么好啊？
Did Hsio have such a good body?
你真的看见秀秀了？
You really saw her?
当然啦，我阴阳眼叫假的啊？
Of course
她刚刚身上穿的纱我都帮她拆下来了
I took off the silk she was wearing
那我也要看可不可以啊？
Can we watch too?
可以啊
Sure
怎么办？
Now what?
只要能够找到她生前穿的衣服，我就有办法
If I can find her clothes, then I'll know
真的？
Really?
阿星，你真的要买纸钱烧给秀秀？
Sing, you want to give her some money?
你没听我爹说，他看到秀秀没有穿衣服吗？
Didn't you hear, Hsio doesn't have clothes?
那要不要烧些钱给她？
Should we give her some money?
当然要啦，我还要烧一栋房子给她
Of course, and a house too
最好连汽车也一块烧
And also a car
总之啊，她缺什么，我就烧什么嘛
Whatever she needs, I give her
你帮我想想看，我还要烧些什么东西给秀秀？
Help me think, what else would she need?
我想到了，不过你一定不肯烧给她的
I know, but you probably won't do it
说嘛，怎么会呢，我这么爱秀秀
Why not, I love her
有什么我不肯烧给她的？
What wouldn't I give her?
你真的肯答应啊？
You really would?
是啊，快说啦
Yes, tell me
她还缺什么？
What else does she need?
一个男朋友，我就知道你不肯烧给她嘛
A boy friend, see I knew you wouldn't do it
其实我也不会这样想啦
I'm just kidding
秀秀在阴间
She's in the after life
她一定能够找一个比我还要好的男朋友的
She can probably find a better boy friend
秀秀在阴间找男朋友
Hsio find a boy friend in the after life
那你是不是打算在阳间再找个女朋友？
Then you plan on getting a new girl friend?
我像这种人吗？
Do I look like that type of person?
像我这样的男人
A man like me
我要为秀秀守节，终身不娶老婆
I'll never marry
这么巧啊
What a coincidence
是啊，是啊
Yeah
姑娘，你们两个认识啊？
Miss, you know each other?
师兄，怎么不给我介绍一下？
Brother, why don't you introduce us?
他是我师弟，叫阿森
He's my younger brother, Sen
你好
Hello
这位姑娘叫.
Your name is...
我叫波波
My name is Po
波波
Po
波波，好可爱的名字
Po, what a cute name
我赶着帮我爹送酒，那我先走了，再见
I have to go, bye
走啦
Let's go
阿星，你跟她认识很久了？
Sing, have you known her long?
很久了，她一直在追我嘛
Pretty long, she likes me
真的啊？
Really?
你不相信？
You don't believe me?
信，信，信，她又追来了
Of course, she's back
波波，有什么事？
Po, what's wrong?
没什么啦，我忘了问你叫什么名字？
I forgot to ask you your name?
我叫阿星
Sing
星哥，森哥，那我走了
Sing, Sen, I'm leaving
再见
Bye
你们认识很久了？
You've known each other long?
她实在可爱，知不知道她住在那？
She's cute, I wonder where she lives?
喂，你喜欢她吗？
Do you like her?
你不可能又看上她了吧？
You like her too?
怎么不可能啊？
Why not?
你刚才不是说要为秀秀守节，不娶老婆的？
I thought you weren't going to marry?
我是说我终身不娶老婆，可没说我终身不娶侍妾
I meant a wife, a concubine is different
这小子
You rascal
昨天晚上我见到秀秀
I saw Hsio last night
好可怜，连衣服都没得穿
Poor girl, didn't even have clothes to wear
我才不相信呢，秀秀要我烧衣服给她
I'm going to give her some
她为什么不托梦给我？
Why doesn't she appear in my dreams?
我老早跟你说过了，你的八字很硬
I told you, you're too strong
他们都不敢托梦给你呀
Ghosts are afraid to appear in your dreams
你想想看
Think about it
你老公死了以后有没有托梦给你啊？
Did your ex-husband appear in your dreams?
这倒是，可是我还是不相信你见过秀秀
True, but I still don't believe you saw Hsio
你真的不相信？
You really don't?
你看看
Look
你眼睛干嘛？
What are you doing?
长针眼啊
Stye
现在你相信我看到秀秀没穿衣服了吧？
Do you believe I saw Hsio naked now?
孩子，娘也不知道要烧衣服给你
My child, Mom didn't know
娘看你这些个衣服都太日了
All your clothes are old
娘这几件衣服是刚结婚的时候穿的
I bought these clothes when I got married
还很新，我想，你会喜欢的
They're still new, you'll like it
娘这就去化给你
Mom will give them to you
如果偷到秀秀的衣服，就可以作法见到她了
With Hsio's clothes I can conjure her up
胡妈妈进去了，你快去偷衣服啊
Mrs. Hu's gone, let's go
可以胡妈妈她看到衣服不见了，那怎么办？
But what if Mrs. Hu notices?
顺便到白寡妇那儿去偷几件衣服来
Go steal some clothes from Mrs. Pal
快啊，快啊
Hurry
快走，快走.
Hurry...
你是胡秀秀吗？
Are you Hsio?
是啊
Yeah
你的家人在阳间烧衣服给你了，你点收一下吧
Your relatives gave you some clothes, keep it
拿去
Take it
谢谢鬼差大人
Thank you
我真的能看到秀秀吗？
Can I really see Hsio?
当然啦，少爷，别吵我作法嘛
Of course, be quiet
到那边去看着
Let go over there
说真的，到底行不行啊？
Are you sure?
不止行，而且很厉害呢
Definitely
那就看你的了
It's in your hands
脚踏七星步步升
Stepping on the stars
天上三奇日月星，通天通地鬼神惊
Sun moon star
助我灵威展威灵
Help me conjure up the ghost
怎么样，厉害吧？
Not bad, eh?
你行，我看你的法力就跟这张桌子一样的烂
I think it sucks
不要紧，我还有一道符
I have another trick
天圆地方，律令九章
Round sky, square earth
飞符上身，急降我旁
Come land next to me
看你这么烂的法术，就别在丢人现眼了
Stop embarrassing yourself
算了，走，走，不要做了
Forget it, let's go
行了，行了，搞定了
Yes, this is it
这会是秀秀吗？我看你把你妈变出来了
Is this Hsio? I think it's Mrs. Hu
胡妈妈？
Mrs. Hu?
急急如律令，撤
Hurry hurry disappear
怎么会变成胡妈妈？
How can it be Mrs. Hu?
少爷，好像有些什么东西不对劲
I think something is wrong
是啊，我知道什么不对劲
Yes, I know what's wrong
什么？
What?
就是你不对劲
You're what's wrong
没道理啊，奇怪了
That doesn't make sense, strange
波波，明天我们就回西藏去
Po, let's go back to Tibet tomorrow
为什么不多留几天呢？
Why not stay longer?
你也看得出来
You know why
南方人是没有办法接受我们的密宗的
The southerners can't accept our religion
其实佛教跟密宗根本就是一家嘛
Our religion and theirs were once the same
我看啊你是多花一点时间来感化他们
I think you should try to convert them
教训我啊
Stop lecturing me
我看你是想多玩几天吧
I think you want to play a few more days
爹，你真了解我
Dad, you really understand me
葛少爷，请喝茶，今天要吃点什么？
Mr. Ko, what would you like?
不要罗嗦，照日照日
The usual
快点，快点
Hurry
好好好，马上就来
Yes, right away
哇，少爷，正点耶
Look master, she's gorgeous
这姑娘怎么以前没见过？
How come I never seen her before?
可能是外地来的吧？
She might be from our of town
少爷，去泡她
Go for her
对
Yeah
爹，多吃一点
Have some more
他旁边那个老头子可能不是什么善男信女
Watch out for that old man next to her
少爷，你怕什么，说打嘛，有联军在就够了
We have Lieng with us
说钱嘛，你身上有的是啊
Plus you have plenty of money
对啊
That's right
过去吧
Go over
先想办法把那个老头调开
Try to lure the old man away
少爷，我有办法啦
I got it
什么办法？
What?
我先寺放水
I have to go to the bathroom first
少爷，你别不住了？
Can't you hold it?
老头，我要泡这个女人，麻烦你让开
Old man, I want to make the moves on her
你神经病啊？
Are you crazy?
我就是神经病，所以才泡你啊
Exactly
打是爱，再打，再打啊
Hitting is loving, hit me
你干嘛打我？
Why did you hit me for?
你刚刚调戏我，不打你打谁啊？
You were flirting with me?
小兄弟，你已经被鬼上身
Kid, there's a ghost on you
鬼？鬼在那里啊？
Ghost? Where?
好，我让你看看
Take a look
你现在可以看到了
You can see her now
秀秀
Hsio
你不要过来.
Don't come over...
走开
Go away
救命啊.
Help...
别跑
Stop
走开，放开我.
Let me go...
他们在干什么？
What are they doing?
救命啊.
Help me...
爹，发生什么事？
Dad, what happened?
我好像听到秀秀喊救命
I think I heard Hsio crying for help
那我要去救她，她在那里？
Where is she?
你是人她是鬼，你怎么救她？
How are you going to do that?
爹，你帮我作法离魂啊
Dad, help me.
又不知道他在搞什么鬼
I wonder what he's up to
爹，你拿花瓶做什么？
Dad, what are you doing with the vase?
你干嘛打他？
Why did you hit him?
因为他的功力还不够，作法之前要把他打晕才行
Because he's too weak.
天心正法，神人合心，通天达地，火速奉行
Sky's heart, united heart, straight through
星哥
Sing.
大师，救我.
Save me...
波波，让开
Po, step aside.
爹，有人在叫我
Dad, someone calling me.
你先让开
Step aside first.
星哥，你怎么样？
Sing, are you OK?
走
Leave...
厉害，厉害.
Tough, tough...
多谢大师救我
Thank you for saving me.
大师，我们少爷仰慕你很久了
My master has admired you for a long time.
这个我.
Well...
无所谓啦，都算我的好了
It's all on me.
星哥，没想到你会来救我
Sing, I can't believe you're here to save me.
你怎么穿成这个样子？
Why are you like this?
我也搞不清楚我娘怎么烧这些衣服给我
I can't understand why my mom gave me these.
不过也蛮好看的，秀秀，我好想你
They're OK, Hsio I miss you.
我也是
Me too.
他应该已经救了秀秀了，怎么魂魄还不回来呢
He should have saved Hsio by now.
他在干什么？
What is he doing?
你说呢？
What do you think?
不会吧？
Nah?
兔崽子
Damn kid.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
鸡啼，天亮了，我要走了
It's day light, I must go.
秀秀
Hsio.
星哥，再不走，太阳一出我就会魂飞魄散
Sing, go now.
你也是一样，赶快走吧
You too, go.
秀秀
Hiso
你走吧，快啊
Go, hurry
怎么不动了？
Why isn't he moving?
动了那么久还不够，我看他是虚脱了
I think he's exhausted.
星仔他年轻力壮的，动一个晚上也没关系的
Shing's young, he should last all night.
想当初，我刚结婚的时候，我老公他也行啊
When I first got married, my husband could
所以他死那么早啊
That's why he died so soon.
兔崽子，天都快亮了还不回来
Damn kid, he's still not back.
我看他是不想回来了
I don't think he wants to
你终于舍得回来了
Finally.
爹，胡妈妈
Dad, Mrs. Hu.
阿星，说实话，昨天晚上你救了秀秀之后
Tell me, after you saved Hsio.
你是不是跟她.
Did you...
我跟秀秀怎么样啦？
Did we what?
你少跟我装蒜，是不是跟她作爱了？
Did you make love to her?
拜托你，斯文一点好不好？
Please, can you be more tactful?
作爱还不斯文，怎么样才斯文啊？
What's more tactful?
你应该问他，是不是跟秀秀交配了？
You should ask, did you and Hsio mate?
或者说呢阿星是不是把秀秀给占有了？
Or did you take Hsio?
阿星，到底有没有啊？
Sing, did you or didn't you.
真的？
Really?
胡妈妈，你别误会
Mrs Hu, don't get the wrong idea.
是秀秀她自愿的，我可没有逼她啊
She wanted to, I didn't force her.
想不到我晚年的幸福
My happiness.
毁在你昨天晚上的一时冲动
Was destroyed by your urges last night.
昨天晚上星仔他是对着秀秀冲动
His urges was towards Hsio.
他又不是对着你的
Not you.
你的幸福怎么会断送在他手上呢？
How did you lose your happiness?
你这个笨女人，秀秀跟星仔已经交配了
You dumb woman, they've mated.
我们就成了亲家了
That means were in-laws.
我就不能对你有任何企图
Which means I can't marry you.
你说，我下辈子是不是毁了？
Isn't that destroying my happiness?
谁叫你要晚了一步呢？要是你早点冲动的话
Who told you to act so late.
就不会连我的幸福也断送在他们的手上了
We wouldn't lose our happiness on them.
胡妈妈，我爹他一大把年纪了
Mrs. Hu, my Dad is too old.
不会给你太多幸福的
He wasn't give you too much happiness.
阿星
Sing.
爹，要不是昨天晚上，波密大师出手帮我的话
Dad, if this priest didn't help me last night.
我就被阿星跟秀秀给害死了
I would have been killed by Sing and Hsio.
葛少爷，你也不要高兴得太早
Mr. Ko, don't start celebrating too early.
我已经帮你算过了，你的劫数还没有过呢
Your bad luck has not passed yet.
我真的过不了二十三岁啊？
I'll really not live past 23.
什么，你才二十三啊？
You're only 23?
那为什么看起来像四十三呢？
Why do you look like 43?
我属于少年老成型的
I mature quickly.
大师，我儿子到底有没有得救啊？
Priest, can you save my son?
其实他前一阵子就有一个劫，早就该一命呜呼了
He should have died long ago.
能够活到今天，也算是一个奇迹啊
It's a miracle that he's still alive.
再下来这个劫，能不能过
Can he overcome the next incident.
就得要看他的造化了
That depends.
大师，你要是能救了我的话
Priest, if you can save me.
我就答应做你的女婿
I'll be your son-in-law.
爹，我们走啦
Dad, let's go.
波波姑娘，我是跟你开玩笑的啦
Miss Po, I'm just joking.
你爹到这里来，无非就是想要宏扬密宗佛法
You're here to spread your region.
只要你们能够帮得了我，我爹绝对肯拿钱出来
If you can save me, I'll donate some money.
盖一座密宗佛庙，让你们能够安定下来
So you can build a temple, and stay here.
把密宗发扬光大
And spread your religion.
真的，大师，请你务必救救我儿子
Please save my son.
好，我会全力保住他
I'll do my best.
不过这一次可能要委屈你了，葛少爷
It might be rough on you Mr. Ko.
只要我能够逃过一劫，什么委屈都没关系啊
As long as I can live past this I don't mind.
秀秀头七都快过了，到现在还报不了仇
Hsio still haven't revenged her death.
秀秀不但报不了仇，连鬼门关报到都没去
She can't report to the after life.
过了今晚子时就进不了鬼门关
After tonight she won't be able to pass.
以后就成了孤魂野鬼了
Then she'll be a lone ghost in the wild.
爹，这怎么办呢？
What should we do?
当然要赶快通知她，叫她去鬼门关报到
We must notify her.
好转世投胎啊
So she can be reincarnated.
爹，那你赶快像上次一样，帮我作法离魂
Dad, do the magic stuff.
让我去通知她啊
So I can notify her.
你千万不要一时冲动，延误过子时
Don't stay past midnight.
我知道
I know.
你干嘛把他打晕啊？
Why did knock him out?
你上次不也是把他打晕的吗？
Didn't you do that last time?
这次只要作法就行了
Magic alone is enough this time.
对不起啊
Sorry.
葛少爷，你要等到死期过了以后才能够出来
Mr. Ko, don't come out.
大师，你放心，我不会偷溜出来的
Don't worry priest.
临
Some
兵
Soldier.
斗
Dual
者
Person
皆
Both
阵
Pattern
裂
Split
再
Again
前
Forward
大师，长寿关在里面，真的安全吗？
Is long-life really safe in there?
放心啦，这个宝塔
Don't worry
只有我和我爹才知道怎么开
Only my dad and I know now.
没有人会闯进去伤害你儿子的
No one will harm him
葛老爷，还有一件事情需要你的合作
Mr. Ko, one more thing.
什么事啊？
What?
因为你是葛少爷的血亲
Because you're related to your son.
我有办法帮他逃过一劫，可是五行相克
If he dodges his bad luck.
我怕他的劫数会祸延到你身上
It might get on you.
大师，那该怎么办啊？
Then what should I do?
我有一个办法
I know.
那就是.你死
You must... die.
葛老爷，为了避免血亲受到牵累，引来相克
In order for your relatives to be safe.
我先施法让你断气，就算是有人来闹
I'll make you stop breathing, in case someone comes.
看到我们在办丧事，他也不好意思来闹了
And sees the funeral, they won't disrupt us.
我断了气，会不会就此嗝屁啊？
Won't I die if I stop breathing?
不会的，等时辰一到，我爹一作法
No, my dad will use magic to bring you back.
你马上就可以醒过来的
It won't take too long.
阴阳眼，老么，养兵千日用兵一时
You two
时辰一到，记得提醒波密大师叫醒我
Remind the priest to wake me.
知不知道？
Understand?
是，老爷，您安心去吧
Yes sir.
就这么说好了
Then it's settled.
现在，你们守着灵堂吧
Go prepare now.
秀秀，我爹要我来找你
Hsio, my dad told me to find you.
要你在子时之前，一定要进鬼门关报到
You must report to the gate of death.
否则啊，你就变成孤魂野鬼了
Otherwise you'll be a wild ghost.
现在什么时候了？
What time is it?
就快要子时，没关系，我送你到鬼门关，走
It's almost midnight, hurry.
等一等，我已经学会用飞的了
Wait, I learned to fly.
真的？
Really?
鬼门关到了，星哥，我要进去了
We're here, I must go in.
我想我们只有来世再见了
I'll see you in the next life.
星哥，你要多保重
Sing, take care.
秀秀
Hsio.
叫什么名字？
Name?
李联杰
Lee.
档案号码
File number
民国五年六月四号
June 4, 1971
星哥
Sing
秀秀
Hsio.
怎么了？
What?
我不回去，我们在人间不能白头到老
I'm not going back.
我决定在阴间跟你做一对鬼夫妻
We can be a ghost couple.
干什么，回去
What are you doing, go back.
好了，下一位
Ok, next.
你叫什么名字？
Name?
我叫王明星
Sing Wang.
档案号码呢？
File Number?
什么档案号码？
What file number?
就是你的生辰八字啊
Your birth date
我是民国三年二月初十生的
February 10th, 1915
岂有此理，阳寿未尽竟敢偷渡入境
You're not completely dead yet.
秀秀，你怎么也被轰出来了？
Hsio, why did you get kicked out?
他们说我阳寿未尽，要把我遣返阳间
They say I'm not completely dead yet.
什么，你也阳寿未尽？
What, you too?
真的，秀秀阳寿未尽啊？
Really, Hsio is not completely dead.
是啊
Yeah.
那你快点把秀秀的魂魄给捉回来啊
Then hurry up and catch her spirit.
阿森，立刻准备东西，到秀秀灵堂起坛
Sen, prepare the stuff?
是，师父
Yes, master.
爹，秀秀真的可以活过来吗？
Dad, can Hsio really come alive?
符令，符令，头带天清
Clear, clear sky
脚踏七星，勒天天灵灵
Stepping on the seven stars.
勒鬼鬼灭形，勒地地灵灵
Ghosts back off.
左手开天门，右手开鬼门
Open the doors to death.
急急如律令
Hurry, hurry
阿星，请鬼差引路
Sing, let the ghost lead the way.
鬼差神驿，请接引路钱
Please pay the toll fee
秀秀，你快点回来
Hsio come back.
三元之下，形影悠悠
Light images.
胡妈妈，秀秀回来了
Mrs. Hu, Hsio's back.
真的吗？
Really?
你可以叫秀秀起床了
You can wake Hsio up now.
秀秀，秀秀，该起床了
Hsio wake up
你已经睡了七天七夜了
You've been sleeping for seven days
秀秀，秀秀，娘在叫你，你听到没有？
Hsio, can you hear me?
秀秀
Hsio
秀秀她怎么动都不动一下呢？
Why isn't she moving?
是不是你的法力有问题啊？
Is there something wrong with your magic?
没有道理啊
There shouldn't be.
阿星，去拔秀秀一撮头发给我
Sing, go get a hair clip for me.
秀秀，对不起啊
Sorry Hsio.
没气味
No Scent.
怎么样？
What?
秀秀是回来了，可是少了一股气
Hsio is back, but she lacks a force.
那怎么办呢？
What now?
秀秀，快点告诉我，当时你是怎么死的？
Hsio tell me how you died?
我记得我当时在冲凉
I remember when I was taking bath,
突然间看见长寿仔从上面跌了下来
I saw Long-life fell down suddenly.
在我还没有失去知觉之前
Before I pass out,
好像还闻到长寿仔的口臭味
I smelled the bad breath from Long-life
原来如此
Oh, I see.
怪不得近来长寿仔的脸色这么好
No wonder Long-life has good complexion these days.
秀秀和你说了些什么？
What did Hsio tell you?
秀秀没有办法醒来是因为
The reason Hsio failed to wake up is because...
她的精气神被长寿仔吸取了
her main force has been taking by Long-life.
什么是精气神？
What's that mean?
人欠一口气，佛欠一缕香
People lack a force Buddha lack a incense
所谓的哪一口气就是精气神
The force is the main force.
爹，那我们该怎么做？
What should we do now, dad?
去找长寿仔将那一口 精气神还给秀秀
Find Long-life and take back the main force for Hsio.
如果过了鸡啼的时间 秀秀就没得救了
If we failed to do that before dawn Hsio will be doomed.
那你们干嘛还站在这里 快点去吧
What are you doing here? Come on.
我们走吧
Let's go, come on.
八叔
Uncle Ba
老葛怎么死了？
Mr. Ko is dead?
是的，八叔，我们老爷已经百年归老了
Yes he is.
八叔也算是我们老爷生前的好朋友
You were a friend of our master.
请到灵前上香吧
So please pray for him
怎么突然之间就嗝屁了？
How did he die?
长寿仔呢？
Where's Long-life?
我家少爷因为伤心过度体力不支
He's weak because of his sadness
现在在房间里面休息
So he's resting in his room
老爹死了躲在房间不肯出来守灵
His father died and he's not even here
这样成何体统啊？
That's ridiculous
真的死了？
Is he really dead?
八叔，你已经瞻仰过我们家老爷的遗容了
You saw his corpse.
现在请回吧
Please leave now.
八叔，你这什么意思？
What's the meaning of this?
我跟老葛是多年的朋友，现在他突然死了
He died too suddenly
我想会不会来被人陷害的
I think he might have been murdered.
所以我要剖腹检查一下
So I want to do an autopsy.
八叔，你看我们家老爷，他死得那么安详
Look, he died so peacefully.
像是被谋害的吗？
Does he look like he's been murdered?
就是因为不像，我才要剖尸检查
No, that's why I have to do an autopsy.
八叔，你是我们家老爷生前的好友
You were a good friend of our master.
为什么要在他的灵前胡闹呢，害他死得不安宁
Why disrupt his funeral
少跟我废话，阿星，叫长寿仔出来
Tell Long-life to get out.
我要问他怎么回事
I want to ask him what's going on.
把他们拦住
Stop them
你们只是家丁
You're only the help
我不想伤害你们，最好不要过来
I don't want to hurt you, don't come over
少跟他罗嗦，谁最卖力
Whoever does the best.
老爷一定重重有赏，上
The master will give them a reward
原来老葛是假死的
So ko isn't really dead
阿森，你没事吧？
Sen are you OK?
师父，我不行了，他好厉害啊
Master, I don't think I can beat him
波波
Po
星哥，怎么会是你呢？
Sing, what are you doing here?
长寿仔是不是在里面？
Is Long-life in there?
我在为他加持祈福，度过劫数
I'm helping him get past his bad luck.
年轻人，我们又见面了
Young man, we meet again
没有用的，塔门一关，任何人都打不开
You're all useless
爹
Dad
波波
Po
大师，你一定有办法，你放长寿仔出来
Priest, let Long-life out.
我急着救人啊
I need to save someone
救谁啊？
Who?
救我的未婚妻啊，他吸走了我未婚妻的真气
My fiance, he stole her breath
我一定要找长寿仔，要回那口气
I need to get her breath back
除非到了时辰，否则开启宝塔会造成很大的危险
Opening the door might be dangerous.
我不能等，过了子时，秀秀就没救了
I can't wait past midnight.
这是天意，我也爱莫能助
This is God's will
什么天意，你根本就是助纣为虐
Nonsense
年轻人讲话不留分寸，小心报应
Watch you mouth
爹
Dad
星哥
Sing
爹，你不要再打他了，他都已经受伤了
Stop hitting him Dad, he's hurt.
只要他不再管这件事，我还可以考虑收他为徒
Only if he stops interfering
你放屁
Bull shit
无极出鞘
Out of the sheathe
五雷轰顶
Thunder lightning
定，出
Set, out
天都快亮了，他们到底在搞什么嘛
It's almost sunrise, what are they doing?
怎么还没争回那口气呢？
Why aren't they back?
星哥，你不要乱动，会很痛的
Sing don't move
不行，时间来不及了，秀秀等着我救她
No, I can't wait.
星哥.
Sing...
星哥，没有用的啦
It's useless.
秀秀，我对不起你，我救不了你，我是废料
Hsio, I'm sorry, I can't save you
秀秀
Hiso
星哥，我可以帮你，快送我上塔顶
Sing, I'll help you
上塔
Go.
好
Alright
站稳了
Steady
爹.
Dad...
快带她去救秀秀
Take her to save Hiso
师父
Master
胡妈妈把秀秀带来了
Mrs. Hu brought Hiso.
天快亮了，时辰要到了
The time is almost up
你们不急啊，我可是急死了
You're not in a hurry, but I am
小心
Careful
长寿仔，他怎么了，你们把他给打死了？
Long-life, what's wrong with him?
他没死，你们放心吧，快救秀秀
He's not dead, save Hiso
爹，对不起
Dad, sorry
没关系，这件事情我不会怪你的，这都是天意
That's alright, it's God's will
大师，波波，谢谢你
Thank you
没什么，我看你对秀秀那么痴情
You're so nice to Hsio
嫁给你，一定会很幸福
She will be really happy married to you
谢谢各位，谢谢
Thank you
爹，葛老爷在那边
Mr. Ko is there
老葛
Ko
来，来，来.
Come, Come
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you
今天我儿子结婚，你得早点到
Today is my son's wedding, please come early
一定，一定
Definitely
人不到没关系，礼一定要到
If you don't show up, your gift must show up
应该的，应该的
Of course
你看，花轿来了，花轿来了
There comes the palankeen.
岳父大人
Father-in-law
波波现在就交给你了
I'll give Po to you now
波波啊
Po
什么波波啊，叫大嫂
Call her sister-in-law
我知道了，大嫂
Sister-in-law
花轿又来了.
There comes another palankeen...
好了，好了，放下，放下来
Ok, put it down
阿星，刚才那个我叫大嫂，这个我叫什么？
Sing, what do I call this one?
这个叫大嫂大，也可以叫大大嫂
Call her big sister-in -law
大嫂大，大大嫂
Big sister-in-law
太复杂了嘛
It's too complicated
好了，星仔，别看了，快进去拜堂吧
Alright, Sing, go in there for the ceremony
你真的要抢亲啊？
You really want to steal my bride?
现在不抢都不行了
It's not up to me any more
可是，你不怕啊？
But, aren't you scared?
我已经过了二十三岁生日怕什么？
What for, I'm over 23
别忘了今年是闰三月，下个月才是你的生日啊
Your birthday is next month.
别吓唬我了
Quit scaring me
不行啦
No way
等一下
Wait
恭喜，恭喜
Congratulations
谢谢，谢谢
Thank you
你好狠，一个都不留给我
Your so mean, didn't even leave one for me
谁叫我长得帅，你长得少年老成呢？
I'm handsome, you're mature
等我过了下个月生日再教训你
Wait until my birthday next month
八叔来我爹，波密大师呢是我岳父
Ba is my dad, the priest is my father-in-law
你有本事教训我吗？
Do you dare touch me?
道术跟密宗手印赢得了洋枪吗？
Can magic and religion beat a gun?
你儿子有毛病啊？
Is your son sick?
他儿子有毛病
His son is sick
毛病，长寿，你干什么？
Sick, Long-life, what are you doing?
他们在干什么？
What are they doing?
我也不知道
I don't know.
对不起，我来晚了，恭喜恭喜
Sorry, I'm late. Congratulations
剧终
The End